<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Event 1</title><link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/4-eventparticipated/4.1-event1/index.html</link><description>Event Summary: “Vietnam Cloud Day 2025: Ho Chi Minh City Connect Edition for Builders” Event Objectives Bring together enterprises, developers, and leaders to explore innovations in cloud computing and AI. Help Vietnam accelerate digital transformation, explore Gen AI technologies, cloud, and new digital solutions for the future Explore advanced solutions from Amazon Web Services (AWS) experts and partners Provide opportunities to connect with the technology community Speakers Eric Yeo : Country General Manager, Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos &amp; Myanmar, AWS Dr. Jens Lottner: CEO, Techcombank Ms. Trang Phung: CEO &amp; Co-Founder, U2U Network Jaime Valles: Vice President, General Manager Asia Pacific and Japan, AWS Jeff Johnson: Managing Director, ASEAN, AWS Vu Van: Co-founder &amp; CEO, ELSA Corp Nguyen Hoa Binh: Chairman, Nexttech Group' Dieter Botha: CEO, TymeX Hung Nguyen Gia: Head of Solutions Architect, AWS Son Do: Technical Account Manager, AWS Nguyen Van Hai: Director of Software Engineering, Techcombank Phuc Nguyen: Solutions Architect, AWS Alex Tran: AI Director, OCB Nguyen Minh Ngan: AI Specialist, OCB Nguyen Manh Tuyen: Head of Data Application, LPBank Securities Vinh Nguyen: Co-Founder &amp; CTO, Ninety Eight Hung Hoang: Customer Solutions Manager, AWS Taiki Dang: Solutions Architect, AWS Key Highlights Leveraging AWS Q to Improve and Enhance Developer Productivity Improve code quality Accelerate solution deployment Provide intelligent programming assistant Maintain strict compliance, privacy, and data security Unlocking Vietnam’s AI Potential AI adoption growth rate reaches 39% 55% of Vietnamese enterprises consider limited digital skills as the main barrier to AI adoption and scaling. Migrate, Modernize and Build on AWS Learn about large-scale migration and modernization strategies on AWS through real-world case studies from Techcombank. Enhance knowledge about application modernization using Generative AI-powered tools, with practical insights from VPBank Gain deep insights from leading industry experts through panel discussions on application modernization Learn about AI-driven cloud modernization specifically for VMware environments Understand AWS security best practices from development to production environments Connect and learn directly from AWS Solutions Architects and industry experts Key Takeaways Why is modernization matter ? Challenges from legacy systems: slowing innovation and increasing costs Benefits of modernization: enabling flexibility, providing deep insights, and driving customer-centric innovation. Impact on business: efficiency, scalability, resilience, competitiveness, and sustainability Modernization Journey Assess: Inventory current environment, identify weaknesses. Mobilize: Establish Center of Excellence (CCoE), build guiding principles, and develop cloud capabilities. Migrate &amp; Modernize: Prioritize high-impact workloads for migration and modernization. Reinvent: Apply artificial intelligence (AI), automation, data products, and new business models. AWS Transform (First agentic AI service for large-scale migration and modernization) Assessment: Build business case for migrating to AWS. VMware: Supporting tools to help migrate from VMware environment to Amazon EC2. Mainframe: Agent to modernize IBM z/OS (mainframe) applications. .NET: Agent to modernize Windows-based .NET applications to Linux platform. Cloud Security Challenges Innovation roadblocks: Traditional security approaches can make security teams seen as barriers to innovation. Expertise &amp; resource shortages: Current security teams are operating at maximum capacity and spending most of their time on repetitive, low-value tasks. Scale and complexity: Managing security at scale in diverse and complex cloud environments is a major challenge. Evolving threat landscapes: New attack tactics and technologies continuously emerge, creating an ever-changing risk environment. Data protection &amp; privacy demands: To maintain customer trust, organizations must meet strict data protection and privacy requirements according to industry regulations (e.g., GDPR, PCI-DSS…). Threat Intelligence is the foundation that helps AWS services respond quickly and proactively to new threats. AWS Shield Amazon GuardDuty Amazon S3 AWS WAF (Web Application Firewall) AWS Network Firewall Amazon Route 53 Resolver DNS Firewall Amazon VPC (Virtual Private Cloud) Event Experience Participating in the workshop “Vietnam Cloud Day 2025: Ho Chi Minh City Connect Edition for Builders” was a very beneficial experience, helping me gain a comprehensive view of application modernization and modern tools. Some notable experiences:</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/4-eventparticipated/4.1-event1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>