<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BlogsTranslated</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/3-blogstranslated/index.html</link>
    <description>Blog 1 - Technology that teaches empathy? How mpathic uses AI to help us listen to each other What if artificial intelligence (AI) could augment our ability to really listen and truly relate to others? What if technology could draw upon our collective lived experiences and help us be more human to each other? These are the questions Dr. Grin Lord, clinical psychologist and founder of conversation analytics company mpathic, has spent the last 15 years chasing.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/3-blogstranslated/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blog 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/3-blogstranslated/3.1-blog1/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/3-blogstranslated/3.1-blog1/index.html</guid>
      <description>Technology that teaches empathy? How mpathic uses AI to help us listen to each other by Bonnie McClure and Chalaire Miller | on 30 APR 2024 | Startup, Startup Spotlight&#xA;On a basic human level, we want to be heard. We want to connect with others, and we want to be understood. Unfortunately, we’re often faced with many things competing for our attention, which makes us bad listeners.Danielle Schlosser, Chief Innovation Officer</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/3-blogstranslated/3.2-blog2/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/3-blogstranslated/3.2-blog2/index.html</guid>
      <description>Tech-savvy savings: innovative ways to cut costs in your small businessn Henrique Trevisan, Jonathan Woods, and Vince Anderson | 23/4/2024 | in Best Practices, Permalink&#xA;Running a small business means making the most of every dollar while maintaining high-quality services. As your business grows and your cloud usage expands, you must find ways to efficiently manage technology resources to protect your bottom line. In today’s challenging economic environment, cost optimization has become a top priority for business owners who want to reduce expenses without sacrificing performance, security, or customer experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/3-blogstranslated/3.3-blog3/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/3-blogstranslated/3.3-blog3/index.html</guid>
      <description>Accelerating the next wave of generative AI startups Swami Sivasubramanian | 13/06/2024 | in AWS for Startups, Featured, Startup, Startup Spotlight | Permalink&#xA;Since day one, AWS has helped startups bring their ideas to life by democratizing access to the technology powering some of the largest enterprises around the world including Amazon. Each year since 2020, we have provided startups nearly $1 billion in AWS Promotional Credits. It’s no coincidence then that 80% of the world’s unicorns use AWS. I am lucky to have had a front row seat to the development of so many of these startups over my time at AWS—companies like Netflix, Wiz, and Airtasker. And I’m enthusiastic about the rapid pace at which startups are adopting generative artificial intelligence (AI) and how this technology is creating an entirely new generation of startups.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Blog 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/3-blogstranslated/3.4-blog4/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/3-blogstranslated/3.4-blog4/index.html</guid>
      <description>Scaling Cloudera’s development environment: Leveraging Amazon EKS, Karpenter, Bottlerocket, and Cilium for hybrid cloud Harpreet Virk and Padma Iyer | 26/09/2025 | in Advanced (300), Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service, Best Practices, Containers, Graviton, Migration, Migration Acceleration Program (MAP) | Permalink |&#xA;This post is co-written with Shreelola Hegde,Sriharsha Devineni and Lee Watterworth from Cloudera.&#xA;Cloudera is a global leader in enterprise data management, analytics, and AI. The Cloudera platform enables organizations to manage, process, and analyze massive datasets, helping businesses across industries like finance, healthcare, manufacturing, and telecommunications accelerate AI/ML adoption and unlock real-time insights.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>