<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intership Report :: My Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/index.html</link>
    <description>Student Information: Full Name: Le Trung Kien&#xA;Phone Number: 0931261009&#xA;Email: trungkien1862@gmail.com&#xA;University: Sai Gon University&#xA;Major: Information Technology&#xA;Class: DCT1213&#xA;Internship Company: AMAZON WEB SERVICES VIETNAM COMPANY LIMITED&#xA;Internship Position: FCJ Cloud Intern&#xA;Internship Duration: From 08/09/2025 to 12/12/2025&#xA;Report Content Worklog Proposal Translated Blogs Events Participated Workshop Self-evaluation Sharing and Feedback</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Worklog</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/1-worklog/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/1-worklog/index.html</guid>
      <description>The content of the tasks carried out in each week is as follows:&#xA;Week 1: Getting familiar with AWS and basic AWS services&#xA;Week 2: Building VPC and Hybrid DNS with Route53&#xA;Week 3: Learn about Compute VM services on AWS&#xA;Week 4: Learn about Amazon S3 storage service&#xA;Week 5: Learn about security services on AWS&#xA;Week 6: Learn about database services on AWS Cloud&#xA;Week 7: Practice deploying applications to aws with docker&#xA;Week 8: Learn how to optimize costs on AWS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposal</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/2-proposal/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/2-proposal/index.html</guid>
      <description>Cost-Optimized SaaS Task Management Platform Single-Region High Availability with ECS Fargate 1. Executive Summary The SaaS Task Management Platform is designed to deliver a Todoist-like collaborative experience with High Availability (HA) and Cost Efficiency, specifically optimized for AWS Free Tier constraints.&#xA;Initially, the project targeted a Multi-Region deployment to achieve the high levels of global performance, disaster recovery (DR), and uptime. However, due to the cost limitations and the constraints of the AWS Free Tier (particularly concerning cross-region data transfer and running multiple primary/replica database instances), the architecture was strategically consolidated into a Single AWS Region (ap-southeast-1 - Singapore).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlogsTranslated</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/3-blogstranslated/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/3-blogstranslated/index.html</guid>
      <description>Blog 1 - Technology that teaches empathy? How mpathic uses AI to help us listen to each other What if artificial intelligence (AI) could augment our ability to really listen and truly relate to others? What if technology could draw upon our collective lived experiences and help us be more human to each other? These are the questions Dr. Grin Lord, clinical psychologist and founder of conversation analytics company mpathic, has spent the last 15 years chasing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EventParticipated</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/4-eventparticipated/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/4-eventparticipated/index.html</guid>
      <description>During my internship, I participated in two events. Each one was a memorable experience that provided new, interesting, and useful knowledge, along with gifts and wonderful moments.&#xA;Event 1 Event Name: Vietnam Cloud Day 2025 : Ho Chi Minh City Connect Edition for Builders&#xA;Date &amp; Time: 09:00, August 13, 2025&#xA;Location: 26th Floor, Bitexco Tower, 02 Hai Trieu Street, Saigon Ward, Ho Chi Minh City&#xA;Role: Attendee&#xA;Event 2 Event Name: AWS CLOUD MASTERY SERIES #3 – Security on AWS</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshop</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/index.html</guid>
      <description>Cost-Optimized SaaS Task Management Platform Overview SGU TodoList is a robust and resilient task management application built using a Microservices architecture designed for high scalability and decoupling. The primary goal of this workshop is to guide you through deploying and managing a complex application stack on the AWS Cloud platform, with a strong focus on cost optimization and serverless operations.&#xA;By leveraging core AWS services such as ECS Fargate, S3, ALB, and VPC, you will learn how to set up an infrastructure that is performant, highly available, and minimizes overhead costs compared to traditional EC2 instances.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/6-self-evaluation/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/6-self-evaluation/index.html</guid>
      <description>During my internship at AMAZON WEB SERVICES VIETNAM COMPANY LIMITED from 08/09/2025 to 12/12/2025, I had the opportunity to learn, practice, and apply the knowledge acquired in school to a real-world working environment.&#xA;I participated in learning and working with AWS services while building a Todoist-like task management application, through which I improved my skills in problem-solving, teamwork, self-learning, and application development.&#xA;In terms of work ethic, I always strived to complete tasks well, complied with workplace regulations, and actively engaged with colleagues to improve work efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feedback</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/7-feedback/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/7-feedback/index.html</guid>
      <description>Overall Evaluation 1. Working Environment&#xA;The working environment is friendly and welcoming. Everyone is willing to support and motivate each other in their tasks. The workspace is modern, tidy, and comfortable. 2. Support from Mentor / Team Admin&#xA;The mentors and admin team members always provide clear and detailed guidance, as well as support with procedures and learning materials, helping me complete the internship process smoothly. They are also willing to share knowledge based on their personal work experience. 3. Relevance of Work to Academic Major</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>