<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EventParticipated :: My Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/4-eventparticipated/index.html</link>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <description>During my internship, I participated in two events. Each one was a memorable experience that provided new, interesting, and useful knowledge, along with gifts and wonderful moments.&#xA;Event 1 Event Name: GenAI-powered App-DB Modernization workshop&#xA;Date &amp; Time: 09:00, August 13, 2025&#xA;Location: 26th Floor, Bitexco Tower, 02 Hai Trieu Street, Saigon Ward, Ho Chi Minh City&#xA;Role: Attendee</description>
=======
    <description>During my internship, I participated in two events. Each one was a memorable experience that provided new, interesting, and useful knowledge, along with gifts and wonderful moments.&#xA;Event 1 Event Name: Vietnam Cloud Day 2025 : Ho Chi Minh City Connect Edition for Builders&#xA;Date &amp; Time: 09:00, August 13, 2025&#xA;Location: 26th Floor, Bitexco Tower, 02 Hai Trieu Street, Saigon Ward, Ho Chi Minh City&#xA;Role: Attendee&#xA;Event 2 Event Name: AWS CLOUD MASTERY SERIES #3 – Security on AWS</description>
>>>>>>> dev
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/4-eventparticipated/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Event 1</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/4-eventparticipated/4.1-event1/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/4-eventparticipated/4.1-event1/index.html</guid>
      <description>Event Summary: “Vietnam Cloud Day 2025: Ho Chi Minh City Connect Edition for Builders” Event Objectives Bring together enterprises, developers, and leaders to explore innovations in cloud computing and AI. Help Vietnam accelerate digital transformation, explore Gen AI technologies, cloud, and new digital solutions for the future Explore advanced solutions from Amazon Web Services (AWS) experts and partners Provide opportunities to connect with the technology community Speakers Eric Yeo : Country General Manager, Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos &amp; Myanmar, AWS Dr. Jens Lottner: CEO, Techcombank Ms. Trang Phung: CEO &amp; Co-Founder, U2U Network Jaime Valles: Vice President, General Manager Asia Pacific and Japan, AWS Jeff Johnson: Managing Director, ASEAN, AWS Vu Van: Co-founder &amp; CEO, ELSA Corp Nguyen Hoa Binh: Chairman, Nexttech Group&#39; Dieter Botha: CEO, TymeX Hung Nguyen Gia: Head of Solutions Architect, AWS Son Do: Technical Account Manager, AWS Nguyen Van Hai: Director of Software Engineering, Techcombank Phuc Nguyen: Solutions Architect, AWS Alex Tran: AI Director, OCB Nguyen Minh Ngan: AI Specialist, OCB Nguyen Manh Tuyen: Head of Data Application, LPBank Securities Vinh Nguyen: Co-Founder &amp; CTO, Ninety Eight Hung Hoang: Customer Solutions Manager, AWS Taiki Dang: Solutions Architect, AWS Key Highlights Leveraging AWS Q to Improve and Enhance Developer Productivity Improve code quality Accelerate solution deployment Provide intelligent programming assistant Maintain strict compliance, privacy, and data security Unlocking Vietnam’s AI Potential AI adoption growth rate reaches 39% 55% of Vietnamese enterprises consider limited digital skills as the main barrier to AI adoption and scaling. Migrate, Modernize and Build on AWS Learn about large-scale migration and modernization strategies on AWS through real-world case studies from Techcombank. Enhance knowledge about application modernization using Generative AI-powered tools, with practical insights from VPBank Gain deep insights from leading industry experts through panel discussions on application modernization Learn about AI-driven cloud modernization specifically for VMware environments Understand AWS security best practices from development to production environments Connect and learn directly from AWS Solutions Architects and industry experts Key Takeaways Why is modernization matter ? Challenges from legacy systems: slowing innovation and increasing costs Benefits of modernization: enabling flexibility, providing deep insights, and driving customer-centric innovation. Impact on business: efficiency, scalability, resilience, competitiveness, and sustainability Modernization Journey Assess: Inventory current environment, identify weaknesses. Mobilize: Establish Center of Excellence (CCoE), build guiding principles, and develop cloud capabilities. Migrate &amp; Modernize: Prioritize high-impact workloads for migration and modernization. Reinvent: Apply artificial intelligence (AI), automation, data products, and new business models. AWS Transform (First agentic AI service for large-scale migration and modernization) Assessment: Build business case for migrating to AWS. VMware: Supporting tools to help migrate from VMware environment to Amazon EC2. Mainframe: Agent to modernize IBM z/OS (mainframe) applications. .NET: Agent to modernize Windows-based .NET applications to Linux platform. Cloud Security Challenges Innovation roadblocks: Traditional security approaches can make security teams seen as barriers to innovation. Expertise &amp; resource shortages: Current security teams are operating at maximum capacity and spending most of their time on repetitive, low-value tasks. Scale and complexity: Managing security at scale in diverse and complex cloud environments is a major challenge. Evolving threat landscapes: New attack tactics and technologies continuously emerge, creating an ever-changing risk environment. Data protection &amp; privacy demands: To maintain customer trust, organizations must meet strict data protection and privacy requirements according to industry regulations (e.g., GDPR, PCI-DSS…). Threat Intelligence is the foundation that helps AWS services respond quickly and proactively to new threats. AWS Shield Amazon GuardDuty Amazon S3 AWS WAF (Web Application Firewall) AWS Network Firewall Amazon Route 53 Resolver DNS Firewall Amazon VPC (Virtual Private Cloud) Event Experience Participating in the workshop “Vietnam Cloud Day 2025: Ho Chi Minh City Connect Edition for Builders” was a very beneficial experience, helping me gain a comprehensive view of application modernization and modern tools. Some notable experiences:</description>
    </item>
<<<<<<< HEAD
=======
    <item>
      <title>Event 2</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/4-eventparticipated/4.2-event2/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/4-eventparticipated/4.2-event2/index.html</guid>
      <description>Event Summary: “AWS CLOUD MASTERY SERIES #3 – Security on AWS” Event Objectives A deep-dive sharing session that helps participants understand the 5 security pillars of the AWS Well-Architected Security Pillar and how to protect cloud systems against increasing threats.&#xA;Sharing about security-supporting services and system auditing methods to protect AWS accounts and systems from attacks.&#xA;An opportunity to connect with the First Cloud Journey community.&#xA;Speakers Le Vu Xuan An: AWS Cloud Club Captain HCMUTE, First Cloud AI Journey Tran Duc Anh: AWS Cloud Club Captain SGU, First Cloud AI Journey, Cloud Security Engineer Trainee Tran Doan Cong Ly: AWS Cloud Club Captain PTIT, First Cloud AI Journey Dang Hoang Hieu Nghi: AWS Cloud Club Captain HUFLIT, First Cloud AI Journey Nguyen Tuan Thinh: First Cloud AI Journey, Cloud Engineer Trainee Huynh Hoang Long: First Cloud AI Journey, Cloud Engineer Trainee Dinh Le Hoang Anh: First Cloud AI Journey, Cloud Engineer Trainee Nguyen Do Thanh Dat: First Cloud AI Journey, Cloud Engineer Trainee Van Hoang Kha: First Cloud AI Journey, Cloud Engineer Trainee Thinh Lam: First Cloud AI Journey Viet Nguyen: First Cloud AI Journey Mendel Grabski (Long): ex Head of Security &amp; DevOps, Cloud Security Solutions Architect Tinh Truong: AWS Community Builder, Platform Engineer at TymeX Key Highlights Identity &amp; Access Management Service Understand what IAM is used for Best practices for using IAM in system security SCP and permission boundaries for multi-account setups MFA, credential rotation, Access Analyzer Detection &amp; Continuous Monitoring CloudTrail (org-level), GuardDuty, Security Hub Logging at all layers: VPC Flow Logs, ALB/S3 logs Alerting &amp; automation with EventBridge Detection-as-Code (infrastructure + rules) Infrastructure Protection VPC segmentation, private vs public placement Security Groups vs NACLs: usage models WAF + Shield + Network Firewall Workload protection: EC2, ECS/EKS security basics Data Protection KMS: key policies, grants, rotation Encryption at-rest &amp; in-transit: S3, EBS, RDS, DynamoDB Secrets Manager &amp; Parameter Store — rotation patterns Data classification &amp; access guardrails Incident Response AWS Incident Response lifecycle Playbooks: Compromised IAM key S3 public exposure EC2 malware detection Snapshot, isolation, evidence collection Auto-response using Lambda/Step Functions Key Takeaways How to protect a personal AWS account Apply the Least Privilege Principle for IAM Users Do not use the root account for daily tasks Avoid using “*” in policy actions/resources Enable MFA for enhanced security Overview of GuardDuty An intelligent threat detection service that continuously monitors for malicious activities in AWS accounts and workloads. GuardDuty analyzes data from multiple sources including: AWS CloudTrail logs, VPC Flow Logs, DNS logs (Route 53 Resolver DNS query logs). Can use CloudFormation to build EventBridge rules that trigger Lambda functions and send SNS notifications when GuardDuty detects threats. Principles for building secure systems How to use Security Groups and NACLs to defend against external and internal threats. Understand common attack vectors to react and mitigate in time. Use services like AWS WAF, AWS Network Firewall, and AWS Shield Advanced (for DDoS protection) to strengthen system security both externally and internally. Using KMS to encrypt and protect data Create and manage encryption keys Control who can use or manage these keys Monitor all KMS-related activities with CloudTrail Event Experience Participating in the “AWS CLOUD MASTERY SERIES #3 – Security on AWS” workshop was a highly valuable experience, giving me a broader understanding of how to protect accounts and systems from basic to advanced levels. Some notable experiences:</description>
    </item>
>>>>>>> dev
  </channel>
</rss>