<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop :: My Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/index.html</link>
    <description>Cost-Optimized SaaS Task Management Platform Overview SGU TodoList is a robust and resilient task management application built using a Microservices architecture designed for high scalability and decoupling. The primary goal of this workshop is to guide you through deploying and managing a complex application stack on the AWS Cloud platform, with a strong focus on cost optimization and serverless operations.&#xA;By leveraging core AWS services such as ECS Fargate, S3, ALB, and VPC, you will learn how to set up an infrastructure that is performant, highly available, and minimizes overhead costs compared to traditional EC2 instances.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Overview</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/5.1-workshop_overview/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/5.1-workshop_overview/index.html</guid>
      <description>Project Introduction SGU TodoList is a task management application built using a Microservices architecture on the AWS Cloud platform. The project was initially designed to be deployed as a Multi-Region SaaS model to ensure high availability and disaster recovery. However, due to budget constraints and AWS Free Tier limitations, the team optimized the architecture for a Single-Region Deployment with a Cross-Region Failover mechanism for the frontend.&#xA;Overall architecture Backend Architecture (Single-Region: Singapore) ┌──────────────────────────────────────────────────────┐&#xD;│ Internet Users │&#xD;└───────────────────────┬──────────────────────────────┘&#xD;│&#xD;▼&#xD;┌────────────────┐&#xD;│ Route 53 │ ◄── DNS Management&#xD;│ (Global DNS) │&#xD;└───────┬────────┘&#xD;│&#xD;▼&#xD;┌──────────────────────┐&#xD;│ Application Load │&#xD;│ Balancer (ALB) │ ◄── SSL/TLS Termination&#xD;│ + ACM Certificate │ (sgutodolist.com)&#xD;└──────────┬───────────┘&#xD;│&#xD;┌──────────────┼──────────────┐&#xD;│ │ │&#xD;▼ ▼ ▼&#xD;┌─────────┐ ┌─────────┐ ┌──────────┐&#xD;│ Auth │ │ User │ │Taskflow │ ◄── ECS Fargate&#xD;│ Service │ │ Service │ │ Service │ Microservices&#xD;└────┬────┘ └────┬────┘ └────┬─────┘ (Public Subnets)&#xD;│ │ │&#xD;└────────────┼─────────────┘&#xD;│&#xD;┌────────┴────────┐&#xD;│ API Gateway │ ◄── Central Entry Point&#xD;│ (Port 8080) │ + CORS + Rate Limiting&#xD;└────────┬────────┘&#xD;│&#xD;┌───────────┼─────────────┐&#xD;│ │ │&#xD;▼ ▼ ▼&#xD;┌────────────┐ ┌─────────┐ ┌──────────┐&#xD;│Notification│ │ Kafka │ │ AI Model │&#xD;│ Service │ │ Cluster │ │ Service │&#xD;└──────┬─────┘ └────┬────┘ └────┬─────┘&#xD;│ │ │&#xD;└────────────┼────────────┘&#xD;│&#xD;┌──────────┴──────────┐&#xD;│ │&#xD;▼ ▼&#xD;┌─────────┐ ┌───────────┐&#xD;│ RDS │ │ Redis │ ◄── Data Layer&#xD;│ MySQL │ │ElastiCache│ (Private Subnets)&#xD;└─────────┘ └───────────┘&#xD;Frontend Architecture (Multi-Region Failover) ┌─────────────────────────────────────────────────────────┐&#xD;│ Internet Users │&#xD;└──────────────────────────┬──────────────────────────────┘&#xD;│&#xD;▼&#xD;┌──────────────┐&#xD;│ Route 53 │ ◄── DNS: sgutodolist.com&#xD;└────────┬─────┘&#xD;│&#xD;▼&#xD;┌────────────────┐&#xD;│ CloudFront │ ◄── Global CDN&#xD;│ Distribution │ SSL Certificate&#xD;└────────┬───────┘ Custom Domain&#xD;│&#xD;┌─────────────┴─────────────┐&#xD;│ Origin Group (HA) │&#xD;│ ┌─────────────────┐ │&#xD;│ │ Primary Origin │ │&#xD;│ │ S3 Singapore │ ◄───┼── Main Region&#xD;│ └─────────────────┘ │&#xD;│ │ │&#xD;│ ┌───────▼───────────┐ │&#xD;│ │ Failover Origin │ │&#xD;│ │ S3 N.Virginia │ ◄─┼── Backup Region&#xD;│ └───────────────────┘ │&#xD;└───────────────────────────┘&#xD;│&#xD;┌──────────┴──────────┐&#xD;│ S3 Cross-Region │&#xD;│ Replication (CRR) │ ◄── Auto Sync&#xD;└─────────────────────┘&#xD;Main components 1. Backend Services (ECS Fargate) Service Port Chức năng Dependencies API Gateway 8080 - Điều phối routing&#xA;- CORS handling&#xA;- Rate limiting Redis, All Services Auth Service 9999 - Xác thực JWT&#xA;- OAuth2 (Google)&#xA;- Token management RDS, Redis, Kafka User Service 8081 - Quản lý user profile&#xA;- User CRUD RDS, Redis, Kafka Taskflow Service 8082 - Quản lý tasks&#xA;- Workflows RDS, Redis, Kafka Notification Service 9998 - WebSocket real-time&#xA;- Push notifications RDS, Redis, Kafka AI Model Service 9997 - Task prioritization&#xA;- Smart suggestions Python Flask 2. Infrastructure Components Networking VPC: 10.0.0.0/16 at Singapore (ap-southeast-1) Public Subnets (2 AZs): ECS Tasks, ALB, Bastion Private Subnets (2 AZs): RDS, Redis (data) Security Strategy: Eliminated NAT to save cost (~$30/month) Data Storage RDS MySQL: Primary database, Free Tier (db.t3.micro) ElastiCache Redis: Caching + Rate limiting (cache.t3.micro) Kafka (ECS): Event streaming, Service Discovery (kafka.sgu.local) Load Balancing &amp; SSL Application Load Balancer: HTTPS termination, path-based routing ACM Certificate: sgutodolist.com Target Groups: Each service has their onw target group with health checks Service Discovery AWS Cloud Map: Namespace sgu.local Internal DNS: auth.sgu.local:9999 user.sgu.local:8081 taskflow.sgu.local:8082 notification.sgu.local:9998 ai-model.sgu.local:9997 kafka.sgu.local:9092 Cost &amp; Optimization Important Architectural Decisions Factors Initial Choice Final Choice Savings NAT Gateway 2 NAT (HA) ❌ Not used ~$60/month ECS Compute EC2 Instances ✅ Fargate Spot (0.5 vCPU) ~$40/month RDS Multi-AZ ✅ Single-AZ Free Tier ~$30/month Redis Cluster Mode ✅ Single Node ~$20/month Backend Multi-Region Active-Active ✅ Single Region ~$200/month Frontend HA Multi-Region Active ✅ Failover Only ~$50/month Public Subnet Strategy for ECS Instead of using expensive NAT Gateways, all ECS Tasks are deployed on Public Subnets with Public IP enabled. This allows:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prerequisite</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/5.2-prerequisite/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/5.2-prerequisite/index.html</guid>
      <description>Preamble: Prerequisites for Backend Deployment Before initiating the deployment steps outlined in the Table of Contents, the following foundational tools, configurations, and AWS service setups must be completed to ensure a smooth, secure, and cost-optimized deployment into the ap-southeast-1 (Singapore) region.&#xA;Step Requirement Purpose 1 AWS Account &amp; CLI Access and command-line management. 2 Domain &amp; SSL Securing traffic and global content delivery. 3 Source Code &amp; Artifacts Building the deployable microservice images. 4 AWS Network Foundation Setting up the isolated, highly available VPC structure. I. Tools &amp; Credentials AWS Account Setup: A valid AWS Account is required, and initial billing alerts (AWS Budgets) must be configured to monitor Free Tier usage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Flow</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/5.3-deploy_flow/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/5.3-deploy_flow/index.html</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents This section provides step-by-step guidance for deploying both Frontend and Backend components onto the cloud infrastructure.&#xA;It covers the complete deployment workflow, from build artifacts preparation to production-ready release on AWS services.&#xA;5.3.1. Frontend Deploy&#xA;Guidelines for building, configuring, and deploying the frontend to Amazon S3 + CloudFront with cross-region failover.&#xA;5.3.2. Backend Deploy&#xA;Instructions for deploying backend microservices to AWS ECS/Fargate, including network configuration, load balancing, and service integration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clean Up</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/5.4-clean_up/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/5.4-clean_up/index.html</guid>
      <description>Cleanup Guide This guide provides a comprehensive instruction to completely terminate all deployed AWS resources across the ap-southeast-1 (Singapore) and us-east-1 (N. Virginia) regions. The sequence is optimized to avoid orphaned resources and subsequent charges.&#xA;I. Deployed AWS Services Summary Before proceeding, verify the existence of the following active services in your account:&#xA;Service Category Service/Resource Name Region Purpose Compute/Scaling ECS Cluster/ASG, EC2 Instances ap-southeast-1 Application Hosting Database/Caching RDS DB Instance (Multi-AZ), ElastiCache Redis Cluster ap-southeast-1 Data Persistence &amp; Session Management Networking Application Load Balancer (ALB), Target Groups, NAT Gateway, VPC ap-southeast-1 Traffic Distribution &amp; Internet Access Storage/Artifacts S3 Primary Bucket, S3 DR Bucket, ECR Repositories ap-southeast-1, us-east-1 File Storage &amp; Image Hosting Global/DNS/Security CloudFront Distribution, ACM Certificates, Route 53 Hosted Zone Global (Edge), us-east-1, ap-southeast-1 CDN &amp; SSL Security II. Cleanup Procedure (Step-by-Step) 1. Clean Up Application Layer (ap-southeast-1) We start by eliminating resources that host the application and connect to the database.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mystic Skills</title>
      <link>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/5.5-mystic-skills/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trungkien2543.github.io/fcj-workshopz/5-workshop/5.5-mystic-skills/index.html</guid>
      <description>1. Hugo Commands 1.1&#xA;hugo build&#xD;1.2&#xA;hugo server -D&#xD;2. Git Commands 2.1 Check repository status&#xA;git status&#xD;2.2 List local branches&#xA;git branch&#xD;2.3 List all branches (local + remote)&#xA;git branch -a&#xD;2.4 Switch to another branch&#xA;git checkout &lt;branch-name&gt;&#xD;2.5 Create and switch to a new branch&#xA;git checkout -b &lt;branch-name&gt;&#xD;2.6 Pull the latest updates from remote&#xA;git pull&#xD;2.7 Fetch updates without merging</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>